We don't have the capability of a scanner, so you can't scan and
put the amendment up if you send it to us a day before.
I don't even know if there's a scanner in the building. I think there may
be one downstairs in the clerk's office.
And so putting stuff electronically
up amendments is something New Mexico has
fallen behind with technology driven access.
Well, Mr. Chair, I think it's actually a rule now. We've passed a law,
maybe even said, Representative McQueen, saying that all amendments would actually have to
be posted online. This may be the only, maybe all
due respect, that we don't post these amendments, these documents.
And I just think we should. I think it's public information
and I just think nothing could be more important than a $10 billion budget
from a policy standpoint and everything contained in it. So I
think, Shawn, I mean, with all the other committees and legislature amendments
because of that rule, what is the common practice of things being put
online and how
timely are those really?
Mr. Chair, Senator, you're correct. The joint rule
was passed a year or so ago. Last year was
the first year of implementation.
The posting of the amendments received by committees or when they're put
on in the committee is the role of the committee secretary and
committee staff. But from the council service, we do provide
committee secretaries with PDFs of any proposed amendment or substitute
that's going to be before a committee. And the only exception is
that our duty of confidentiality does flow
directly to you as legislators. And so if you were to tell us not
to distribute that amendment, we do follow your direction
on that. But that is the common practice to deliver the PDFs
to the committee secretary. And then they get put online while they're being discussed.
Mr. Chair, in the, in the Senate, that has been the practice last year.
Okay. And we've done that as soon as they're adopted.
But we can't put the amendment on because we don't know if it's going to
pass or not. So the amendment in the PDF is not put online.
Ling just told me, until the amendment passes, because we don't know what
it does. I mean, we have copies of the amendments. The sponsor
could give them to whoever they wanted if they want to share the amendment.
If you don't want to share the amendment, that's a legislator's prerogative.
But they're not put up there for discussion purposes because the
bill hasn't been amended. And so until they're amended,
the amendment's not on there. And then if you want to amend the bill.
If you want us to draft an amendment, amend the bill entirely.
We'd have to get the amendment drafted in the bill
and then bring the bill back down and then know where
the amendments are, which could be a one or two day process,
depending on how big the bill is.
Anyway, Mr. Chair, to the extent possible, I just personally
like putting it out there ahead of time,
including putting it online, which probably can be done just
as well as after the fact. And so
just like a bill we vote on that hasn't been adopted. But anyway,
I'll just. That's how I feel about it, you know, Mr. Chair, and the same
usual deal. So appreciate the discussion. Thank you.
We all have text messaging, so the lobbyists can text us if
they like the amendments or not. Sure. Probably had some play in the amendment process.
Anyway, Senator Gonzalez, thank you.
And we also have to take the advice from counsel
because sometimes he turns into a substitute.
Any other questions? We're going to be as transparent as we
can, but you know, we get moving in
certain times and it's just
we can't. I can't manage every little detail.
So you're here to talk to us about
bills and. Thank you, Mr. Chair. Yes. You're gonna
sing the old song.
So I was requested, Mr. Chair. Oh, wait now, Senator Gonzalez,
we're gonna need to go into executive. Now you want to make a
motion, Mr. Chair? Some move that we go into executive session.
Second Senator Shindo, any objection to going to executive.
No, we're not talking about personnel, we're going to talk about bills.